UNITE HERE Photographs 6200 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE HERE Photographs
1962-2002
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE HERE
6200 P
12.83 cubic feet
12.8 linear ft.
Photographs.
7514189
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 18, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 27, 2015
Biographical / Historical
UNITE HERE is a labor union in the United States and Canada, that was formed in 2004 by the merger of the Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees (UNITE) and Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE). The membership is made up mainly of workers in the hotel, food service, laundry, warehouse, and casino gaming industries.
In 2005, UNITE HERE left the AFL-CIO and joined the Change to Win Federation along with other unions including the Teamsters, SEIU and the UFCW. In may 2009, Bruce Raynor, president, left UNITE HERE, taking with hiim several local unions and between 105,000 and 150,000 members. They formed Workers United.
September 17, 2009, UNITE HERE announced that it would re-join the AFL-CIO.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6200: UNITE HERE Records 6200/005 P: UNITE HERE Local 23-25 Photographs
Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Textile workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; Textile Workers Union of America; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees; UNITE HERE (Organization); Workers United
7514189
- HERE Display -- from 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  38 photographs -- Photos are mounted on black poster board ready for display
- HERE Display -- from 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  20 Photographs -- Photos are mounted on black poster board ready for display
- HERE Display -- From 1999-2001 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  10 Photographs -- Photos are mounted on black poster board and ready for display
- HERE Display -- From 1999-2001 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  24 Photographs -- Photos mounted on black poster board ready for display
- HERE Display -- From 1999-2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  24 Photographs -- Photos mounted on black poster board and ready for display
- HERE Display -- From 1999-2001 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  40 Photographs -- Photos are mounted on black poster board and ready for display
- Local 2 H (Tweel Importing) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  30 photographs
- Xerox Atlanta (Box 7, Folder 2)
  8 photographs
- Local 14 R (Box 7, Folder 3)
  9 photographs
- Local 23 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  5 photographs
- Local 24-42/Hats (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Local 49 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  3 photographs
- Local 88 - Juvenile Shoe, Aurora, MO (Box 7, Folder 7)
  11 photographs
- Local 125 H Miller Bros. Industries (HATS) Corsicana, TX (Box 7, Folder 8)
  2 photographs
- Local 136 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  1 photograph
- Local 158 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  6 photographs
- Local 158 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  4 photographs
- Local 169 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  45 photographs
- Local 169 - Schott Bros. Perth Amboy, NJ (Box 7, Folder 13)
  37 photographs
- Local 169 - Royal Sportswear, New York, NY (Box 7, Folder 14)
  21 photographs
- Local 169 - Russell Aives Deer Park, NY (Box 7, Folder 15)
  4 photographs; news clippings
- Local 177 Darwood (Box 7, Folder 16)
  17 photographs
- Local 178 Canada (Box 7, Folder 17)
  20 photographs
- Local 180 - Scalamandre (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Local 190 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Excelled Leather & Sheepskin Co. (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Local 199T Piqua, Ohio (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Local 223 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Local 224 T (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Local 247 Eversboro (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Local 300 C (Box 8, Folder 5)
  7 photographs
- Local 303 A/Arrow Shirts Kirchener, Ont. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Local 319 T (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Local 365 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Local 371 Van Baalen Co. Rockland, ME (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Local 427 - English-American Baltimore Jt. Bd. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  19 photographs
- Local 486 - Hathaway Shirt Co. (Waterville, ME) (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Local 551 Levi-Canada (Box 8, Folder 12)
  10 photographs
- Local 563 - Shoe Workers (Box 8, Folder 13)
  12 photographs
- Local 658 T (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Local 741 C (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Local 747 Huntington, W VA (Corbin); See also Local 1044 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Local 779 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Local 794 - St. James, MO; Buy U.S.A. (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Local 388 Allesons Athletic Co., Geneva, NY (Box 8, Folder 19)
  26 photographs
- Local 389 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Local 819- Big Yank- West Point, Mississippi (Box 8, Folder 21)
  22 photographs
- Local 893 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  13 photographs
- Local 1044 - Ashland, KY (Corbin); See also Local 747 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Local 1067 T Globe Int'l., Buffalo, NY (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Local 1071-C Colt Enterprises Inc. Tyler, TX (Box 8, Folder 25)
  9 photographs; news clippings
- Local 1104 - St. Louis, MO (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Local 1166 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Local 1622 - Emporia, VA (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Local 1623 Cookshire, Quebec (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Local 1698 - TRW (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Local 1712 - Fashion Tanning (Box 8, Folder 31)
  15 photographs
- Local 1854 - Galtex (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Local 1934 (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Local 1923 (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Local 1990 (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Local 2539 - Nasco, Puerto Rico (Box 8, Folder 36)
  25 photographs
- HERE Display - from 1999-2001 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  11 Photographs - Photos mounted on black board ready for display
- Organize! Mobilize!: UNITE HERE (Box 9, Folder 2)
  2 copies of broadsides - English on one side, Spanish on one side
- HERE Display - From 1999-2001 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  8 photographs - Photos mounted on board and ready for display
- Conventions (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Cafeteria Employees Union - Local 302 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Shop Chairman Dinner (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Clark Paulsen (Box 11, Folder 4)
- 1972 Milwaukee Convention (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Local 302 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- President Conran - Retirement -- 5/30/1974 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 8)
  46 photographs
- NY State AFL-CIO -- 9/10/1962 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Convention -- St. Louis - 1966 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Election Results (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Automat Contract (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Convention 1999 - Banners & Ceiling (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Merger Convention -- 1995 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous / Photo copies of some photos (Box 11, Folder 15)
- UNITE (Box 11, Folder 16)
- UNITE - Princeton Laundry #1 - Bronx, NY - Aug. 2002; Gary Schoichet photos (Box 11, Folder 17)
  16 photos
- UNITE - Princeton Laundry #2 - Bronx, NY - Aug. 2002; Gary Schoichet photos (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Daycare - Chinatown (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Personalities - UNITE Related - President Mazur (Box 11, Folder 20)
  68 photographs
- UNITE Related - President Mazur (Box 11, Folder 21)
  14 photographs
- Shops (Box 11, Folder 22)
- UNITE Related - President Mazur & Politicians (Box 11, Folder 23)
- UNITE - Jay Mazur & ILG Activities (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Jay Mazur photos (Box 11, Folder 25)
- UNITE Related - President Jay Mazur (Box 11, Folder 26)
- UNITE Related - President Jay Mazur and Susan Cowell (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Crystal Lee Sutton (Box 11, Folder 28)
  photo album -- 16 photographs
- Industrial Powder Coating Inc. (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Job descriptions (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Kmart (Box 12, Folder 3)
  24 photographs
- Kmart - Atlanta -- 3/24/1996 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Kmart Demos 1994 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Kmart - Greensboro (ACTWU) (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Kmart Greensboro (UNITE) (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Martin Luther King, Jr., Sr. and Coretta Scott (Box 12, Folder 8)
  40 photographs
- Martin Luther King, Jr. (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Martin Luther King, Jr. - Demo in Washington, D.C. 1983 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Chicken Pluckers - Koch 1995 (April) (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Kohler Strike (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Kosins - Local 333 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Ku Klux Klan (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Laundry Demos/NY 1990 Tax (Box 12, Folder 15)
  9 slides; 14 photographs
- Laundry Workers (Box 12, Folder 16)
  54 photographs
- Lear Sigler Industry. (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Lebanon Woolen Mills (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Levi-Strauss (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Levi-Strauss (Canton, Miss.) (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Levi-Strauss Charleston, SC Plant Closing (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Levis -- Harlington, Texas (Box 12, Folder 22)
- Lichtenberg Victory/1991 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  36 photographs
- Lichtenberg Co. - Waynesboro, GA (Box 13, Folder 2)
  71 photographs
- Londontown, SC (Box 13, Folder 3)
- London Fog - Local 775 Eldersburg, MD (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Lufty Limited (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Machinery (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Maine (Lewiston Jt. Bd.) & Locals (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Maquiadora - Trip - 1992 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  1 photographs
- Masland Carpet Co. (Box 13, Folder 9)
- McGill, Eula (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Membership Drives (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Mexico (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Midnight Shift Story (Bangor, PA) (Box 13, Folder 13)
- More than a Union 12/1990 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Music (Box 13, Folder 15)
  16 photographs
- NAFTA Demos 1993 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  23 photographs
- NAFTA Demos 1993 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- New Visions (Box 13, Folder 18)
- NY Valet (Box 13, Folder 19)
- Norma Rae (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Oneita (Box 14, Folder 2)
  48 photographs
- Jackson/Shenkman Southern Tour Spring 1990 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Union Maids (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Rolled photograph, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  Hotel Employees & Restaurant Employees International Union, 42nd General Convention, Chicago, Ill., July 8, 1996
- 42nd General Convention - Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees International Union - Chicago, July 8, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  Panoramic photo removed from box 2 - now housed in box 15 (4 OP)